It got Donald Trump, I guess, but I'm
not really seeing the Adam Sandler in
this. In this video, I'm going to show
you how to create any image or any video
you can imagine, all from your local
computer. Once you have this set up, you
won't even need the internet to generate
images and videos. It all happens
completely on your computer. And the
models we'll be playing with are pretty
much completely uncensored, so you can
generate any weird abomination that pops
into your head. But you might be asking,
why would I need an image or video
generator that's not connected to the
internet? Well, for starters, you're not
giving any data to Google or Microsoft
or OpenAI or any big tech company for
that matter, and they can't train on
anything that you do with these models
cuz you didn't send them anything. Or
maybe you live in a remote area or have
connection issues or want to generate
images at 30,000 ft while on a flight to
your mom's house. And of course, well,
there's the use case of making images
for your own private collection.
Nice.
You know what I'm talking about.
Whatever your reason is, I've got you
covered in today's video. So, let's
start with part one, setting up the main
generation software. For this video,
we'll be using Comfy UI and installing
it locally. I'm doing this demo on a
Mac, but the workflow is basically going
to be the same on a PC.
Hello, I'm a Mac.
And I'm a PC. And if you're not familiar
with Comfy UI, it's like this visual
control panel for creating AI generated
images and videos. When you see Comfy UI
for the first time, it looks super
overwhelming. The workflows look like a
giant spaghetti bowl of connected nodes
that seem super complicated. However,
this tutorial is not going to get into
super advanced, comfy UI techniques.
Instead, I want to show you the simplest
possible workflows to use this tool. So,
I'm going to share resources and
shortcuts and simple methods where it
won't even really matter if you do or
don't understand what's happening with
Comfy UI. This tutorial is designed for
anyone to get up and running as quickly
as possible. The Comfy UI rabbit hole
does run super deep and there is so much
customization that you can do, but for
today's tutorial, I want to get you in
and using it as quickly as possible. So,
the absolute simplest way to get Comfy
UI installed on your computer is to head
over to their official website at
comfy.org.
We can see on their website, if we
scroll down here, it's free and open
source. Comfy UI is 100% free and open
source and always will be. No
subscriptions, no hidden costs. Build,
create, and share without limits, and
runs locally fast. Comfy is designed for
performance. Run workflows directly on
your machine for faster iteration, lower
costs, and complete control. It's also
super customizable, which we'll get into
some of those customizations in today's
video. So, let's scroll back to the top
here. We'll click on download, and we've
got two options. Like I mentioned, I'm
on a Mac. I'm going to download it for
Mac. And this is basically an easy
install. Now, you can install from
GitHub if you want. And if you want to
do that, you can head to this
github.com, comfy anonymous/comfy ui
here, and there is a pretty step-by-step
tutorial on how to get it installed. You
can click on manual install, and it will
walk you through it. But again, just
downloading the Windows and Mac
installers skips a whole bunch of steps.
You don't have to think about installing
Python or all the other dependencies
that are required to get Comfy UI
working. So, now that I've got it
downloaded, I'm going to go ahead and
open the download and I'm going to drop
Comfy UI into my applications folder.
And if I go to open Comfy UI, it's now
available to run on my desktop here.
We'll go through the setup process.
Click get started. Select the GPU you
have. I'm on an M3 Ultra, so I'll go
ahead and click next. You can install it
wherever you want. For this
demonstration, I'm going to go ahead and
leave the installation directory the
default here. And we'll click next. Now,
I'm not migrating any sort of existing
installation, so I'm going to skip over
this. And it's up to you whether you
want to leave automatic updates on and
usage metrics on. And we'll go ahead and
install it. Now, it's going to run a
bunch of scripts in the background, but
again, this skips over so many steps
that you would have to do if you were
using the manual process. Once the
installation for Comfy UI is done,
you'll see a page that looks like this
where it says get started with a
template. And this is the easiest way to
set it up. Now, other tutorials will
show you that you can go and download
the models from Hugging Face or Civot AI
or places like that to actually get the
models that you're going to use. And you
can definitely follow those tutorials
and do that. But I find just using these
built-in templates that are already in
the Comfy UI installer is the easiest
way to get going with Comfy UI. And
there's a lot of options. So, check this
out. Like, there's all of these
different Flux image models that you can
quickly get set up. There's other image
models outside of Flux like various
stable diffusion models. We've got video
models like Juan 2.2, Mochi, Hunion
video, text to video, and so much more.
There's also API connections. Now, keep
in mind if you do use these API
connections, these ones you do need to
connect to the internet. This is
basically calling their servers to do
the processing instead of doing it
locally. So if you do decide to use like
an image API or video API or 3D API,
these ones are connecting to servers,
but you can use Comfy UI with really
good models like the Recraft models, the
runway models, the stability models,
idiogram, things like that. But again,
this is not offline models. So let's
move on to part two of this video, which
is generating images with Comfy UI. So
right now, in my opinion, the absolute
best image generation model that can be
run locally on your computer is this
Flux 1 Cade Dev. Now, if I select this,
we'll see it set up this workflow in the
background, but it's telling me I'm
missing everything. I don't have my text
encoders. I don't have my VAE. I don't
have my diffusion models. Nothing is set
up properly. But it's super easy to get
it set up. We just go through and
download each of these. Let's download
our text encoder here. We'll download
this text encoder. Keep in mind, watch
the file sizes. They are often very,
very large, so make sure you've got the
space to do it. But we'll go ahead and
download this text encoder. We'll
download our VAE here. We'll download
our diffusion model, which again, 11 GB,
so keep an eye on that size. But we'll
go ahead and download that. And we'll
let these downloads run. Once they're
all done downloading, we'll be able to
generate images with Flux 1 Craya. And I
could turn off the internet and it will
still work. After a few minutes, all the
models are downloaded and I can go ahead
and close this box and we can see this
is our Comfy UI workflow that it
created. Now, once we get to this
screen, for the most part, you can leave
all of these settings the same. We've
already got our flux model loaded in
here. All of these things can pretty
much stay on the default. We just give
it a prompt. And well, when I give it a
prompt right now of New York City
skyline at night, I get this error that
says trying to convert float 8 blah blah
blah to MPS backend, but it does not
have support for that dype. This is
happening because I'm on a Mac.
I'm a Mac.
If you're on a PC, you're probably not
going to see this error. It will
probably just generate the image for you
right off the bat. But because I'm on a
Mac, it doesn't work with this float 8
style. And I know this is sounding
complicated, but honestly, don't really
stress out about this. So, in order to
fix this issue, I need to get a model
that actually does work on Mac. This FP8
version does not work on Macs. That
needs to be done on a PC. I actually
need to head on over to hugging face and
this URL up here where I can actually
download the main model for Flux 1
Craya. You'll see down here there's flux
one-ca-dev.safe
safe tensors and is a 23.8 GB file, but
this is a file that will actually run on
the M series of Macs where the smaller
one that we tried at first needs CUDA
architecture which requires Nvidia GPUs.
But what you need to know is if you're
on a Mac, this is the one you're going
to need. If you're on a PC, that
previous model that it installed for us
probably worked. So, go ahead and
download this one. It's yes, 24 gigs.
But once you download it, you're going
to go to where you installed Comfy UI.
In my case, it was under the documents
folder, Comfy UI. And then you're going
to go into models. And then you should
have a folder called diffusion models
here. This is where you want to drop
that Flux 1 Craya dev safe tensors file
that's 24 GB. Once that's in there, you
can then restart your Comfy UI
interface. Just close out of it
completely, open it up again, and the
new model should be available. So, if I
click the arrow here, we now see Flux 1
Crayade dev.safe tensors. This is a
model that should run on my Mac. Now, if
I try to run this again, leaving
everything else the same. New York City
skyline at night. Let's click run. And
pretty quickly, we've got our image of a
New York City skyline at night. Let's
try the White House in the middle of the
winter and run this one. And we get a
snowy picture of the White House. And
here's the Eiffel Tower at sunset. If
you need some stock photography, but you
don't want to pay a stock photography
site, you can interrompt like four
business people in suits sitting around
a conference table all shaking hands at
the same time and you get something that
looks like it's straight out of shutter
stock. Now, one of the limitations of
this Flux Craya dev model and I think
pretty much all of the Flux models is
that I don't believe they'll generate
pictures of actual celebrities like
their real likeness. If I plug in Sam
Altman, Mark Zuckerberg, and Elon Musk
fighting in a WWE ring and generate
this, you'll see that it'll most likely
generate people. They just don't really
look anything like the people you asked
them to generate. Although, I guess it
is all three white dudes in a ring, and
they don't look too far off, but it's
not very great at generating people.
Here's what I got when I tried to do
Gary Buucy eating a dozen sausages at
once. Clearly not Gary Buucy, but I
really want to try to push this to its
limit to show that it is pretty dang
uncensored. It just doesn't have like
real celebrities in the training data.
So, let's do a prompt like Mario
reimagined as Scorpion and Luigi
re-imagined as Subzero from Mortal
Kombat. Subzero Luigi is holding
Scorpion Mario's head in his hands while
the spine dangles below it. Thanks,
Dave, for this prompt, by the way.
Fatality. And this is what I got from
that. Not quite what I envisioned. Let
me try some other prompts and see what I
can come up with. No, it kind of mixed
up Mario and Luigi a little bit, but as
you can see, we can get kind of crazy
outputs. I also got it to create some
like crazy horror scenes that most
closed source models will refuse to do
for you. Now, if at any point you want
to go back and look at the images that
you generated, you go to where you
installed Comfy UI and then click into
the output folder. And you can see it
created a Flux Craft folder here. And we
can see all of the outputs that we've
generated with Flux so far right inside
of this folder. And they're available
for us to access and use however we want
on our hard drive, not in a cloud
anywhere. Although these are syncing to
my Apple Cloud. So I guess that's not
totally true in this case. But if you
have Apple Cloud turned off, they won't
be synced to a cloud. So now let's move
on to part three of this video, which is
generating videos offline with Comfy UI.
For this section of the video, I've
actually switched over to my PC.
I also do fun stuff.
You can run these video models on a Mac.
It's just that most of them are
optimized to run with Nvidia GPUs. And
when you try to run these on a Mac,
they're just extremely slow. I mean,
we're talking 20 to 60 minutes to
generate one sixsecond video. So, for
the sake of this video, I switched over
to my PC to make the process a little
bit faster while I'm demoing it to you.
The absolute easiest way to get video
working in Comfy UI is while you're
logged into your Comfy UI desktop app,
come up to workflow, come up to browse
templates where we originally started,
and then over on the left, we have a
video menu. And right now, as of this
recording, the one 2.2 2 family of video
models are the most powerful openweight
models. These are the best models that
you can use offline right now. And we
have a few options here. We've got one
2.214b text to video, one 2.24b image to
video. They separated the two modalities
out. And then you have one 2.25b
video generation, which does both. This
has text and image to video. And you
pick which one you want to use. And this
is a brand new one that was also just
added in 1 2.214b
first and last frame to video. So you
can actually pick a first frame and a
last frame and have it generate a video
that goes between the two frames. If you
have a pretty decent GPU, you can use
any of these 14B models. If you've got a
older slower Nvidia GPU, you're probably
going to want to use this 5B model.
Let's start with the text to video
model. I'm just going to click on this.
It's going to tell me that there's a few
missing models. So, just like before,
I'm going to go through and download
these models. We'll go ahead and grab
them all so we can get this model
working. Once our models are all done
downloading, I can close out of this.
And now we've got our video workflow
here. And we can pretty much leave
everything at the default. We can see
they've got our prompt here. They've
also got a negative prompt, which is
written in Chinese. I don't know what it
says, but supposedly it's a decent
negative prompt, so you could just go
ahead and leave it. But let's go ahead
and generate something that would work
as like stock video. Let's do a drone
shot of the Grand Canyon. And we'll
literally leave everything on its
default settings here and run it. And
after a few minutes, we get this aerial
drone shot of the Grand Canyon. Now,
this model is still pretty slow even on
Nvidia GPUs, but it's a heck of a lot
faster than if you were trying on a Mac.
I want to do a quick test here just cuz
I'm curious if it'll do it. a drone shot
of Zezy Ping's house. As it pans by his
kitchen window, we see him making
pancakes. I just wonder because it's a
Chinese model if it will uh even allow
me to generate this prompt, and I'm just
really curious. So, let's find out. And
here's what we got out of that. I mean,
it kind of just looks like a generic
flyby of a house. I don't think that
that looks like anybody in particular.
Uh I don't think it censored it. It just
didn't get close enough to make out who
was in the video. All right. Now, let's
play with image to video. So, once
again, I'm going to come into workflow,
click on browse templates, come over to
video, and this time we'll do the one
2.21 14b image to video. Again, a couple
missing models, very large models, but
let's go ahead and download them. Once
those are done downloading, I'm going to
close this box here. And we can see that
we load our image right here. I actually
just generated this image. It's supposed
to be Bigfoot taking a selfie. Looks
more like a gorilla taking a selfie, but
we'll go ahead and roll with it. I'll
pull that image in right here. And we'll
do the prompt Bigfoot taking a selfie
video while showing off his campsite.
And we'll come down and click on run
here. And here's what we got out of
that. We can see that it's got a video
and it kind of uh changes angle and we
can see the tent in the background. But
again, very, very slow even on a really
good GPU. So let's go ahead and come
back to browse templates and we'll play
around with the 5 billion parameter
video generation model here which does
both text to video and image to video.
Again download these models here and
then we'll close out of this here and
we've got our pre-built workflow. These
look like crazy spaghetti bowls that are
hard to understand but if you just use
the pre-built workflows you don't really
have to worry about it. So on this one,
it's a smaller model, so it should
actually generate our videos a little
bit faster with a slight hit in quality.
Now, I want to try a prompt that I
wasn't able to get V3 to actually do,
but I was able to get Halo AI to
generate, which was a humansized hot dog
grilling hot dogiz humans on a barbecue.
Let's go ahead and generate that one and
see what we get out of it. And here's
what it generated for us. Obviously
nowhere near as good as what Halo AI
generated for us. That is not a
humansized hot dog. This does not look
like hot dog size humans. But I will
tell you this was a lot faster to
generate using this 5 billion parameter
model over the 14b model. So I tested a
man mowing the lawn in vain because the
lawn is growing faster than he could
mow. Eventually, the lawn consumes the
man, and we can see that the lawn is
definitely getting big behind him. But
it almost looks like it's actually
growing out of him more than anything.
And here's what it looks like when I
give the prompt. A humanoid Honda Civic
cleaning a man with a pressure washer.
And I mean, it actually did a lot better
than V3 or Halo AI did on this specific
prompt when I tried it last time. I did
reword the prompt a little bit better
this time to get it to do what I wanted,
but I mean that's kind of a cool Honda
Civic. And finally, I wanted to test if
it would actually do like real
celebrities and stuff. So, I gave it the
prompt Adam Sandler hugging Donald
Trump. And I mean, it got Donald Trump,
I guess, but I'm not really seeing the
Adam Sandler in this, but it definitely
tried to generate Donald Trump. That
almost looks like it's supposed to be
Kamala, maybe. I I don't know.
We did it. but it will generate Donald
Trump at least. So yeah, that's how you
generate images offline. That's how you
generate videos offline. To recap, just
download the Comfy UI installer for
either Mac or Windows. And then once
you're inside of Comfy UI, click on
browse templates and just use the
pre-built templates. Then you don't have
to really worry about what all this
spaghetti bull craziness is doing
because somebody else already pre-built
it and figured it all out for you. Now,
personally, I don't really have a huge
need to create a lot of uncensored
videos or to create offline. It's just
not a huge need of mine. I still think
the VO3 model and the Halo AI models are
the best models out there for video
generation. But, if you absolutely want
to generate offline and you want to
generate stuff that isn't getting saved
or watched by anybody else's servers,
this is how you do it. I do have a
little bit of concern about where this
is all headed. I mean, you could
literally generate anything you want.
And even if some of these models are
slightly uncensored, since they are
openweight models, people are
fine-tuning them and training them and
adding extra data into them, making them
able to generate literally anything,
even things you probably shouldn't
generate that no human being should ever
want to generate, unfortunately.
This is the world we live in now. I you
can't put this genie back in the bottle.
And I figure might as well learn how to
use this stuff, learn what's out there,
learn what you're capable of doing and
know the technology as opposed to just
completely avoiding it and being scared
of it. Again, a lot of stuff I'm really
really nervous that people are going to
generate with this and a lot of bad
actors are going to do some bad stuff
with this kind of technology. But I know
you watching you're only going to do
good ethical stuff that nobody would
frown upon. So, let's stick to that. And
if you start playing with Comfy UI,
you're going to be ahead of 99% of the
rest of the world who basically only
knows how to use tools like ChatgPT and
VO. If you do want to get deeper into
the weeds and get some really technical
deep dives and learn how Comfy UI works
and learn about additional nodes and
additional ways to optimize Comfy UI, I
highly recommend a couple channels.
There's an a channel called AI Prreneur
and there's a channel called Olivio
Seras. both people that I'm buddies
with, I've chatted with through DMs.
They make absolutely amazing Comfy UI
tutorials. So, I highly recommend
checking out those two channels if you
want to get even deeper into the weeds
and really, really understand how to
make anything you can possibly imagine
with Comfy UI cuz they go a lot deeper
on those types of tutorials. But this
was meant to be the simplest overview,
the fastest way to get up and running
with Comfy UI, generating images and
videos offline. Hopefully that helped
you do that. I really, really appreciate
you tuning in. If you want the latest
and greatest AI tutorials and you want
to stay uptodate with all of the latest
AI news, make sure you give this video a
thumbs up and subscribe to this channel
and I will make sure that more videos
like this show up in your YouTube feed.
Thank you so much for hanging out. Thank
you so much for nerding out and
hopefully I'll see you in the next one.
Bye-bye. Thank you so much for nerding
out with me today. If you like videos
like this, make sure to give it a thumbs
up and subscribe to this channel. I'll
make sure more videos like this show up
in your YouTube feed. And if you haven't
already, check out futuretools.io where
I share all the coolest AI tools and all
the latest AI news. And there's an
awesome free newsletter. Thanks again.
Really appreciate you. See you in the
next one.